Register of the Polish Subject Collection, 1918-2014
Hoover Institution Archives
- SUBJECT FILE, 1791-1995 (Boxes 1-34)
  - 1989-1993 (Text 23)
    - Political parties, 1990-1994 (Text 29)
      - Polska Wspolnota Narodowa (Text 32)
        - Mysl Narodowa Polska, 1990-1991
        - Program
      - Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe
        - Klub Parlamentarny P.S.L. Biuletyn, nos. 8-14, 1992-1993
        - Porozumienie Ludowe (Text 33)
      - Ruch dla Rzeczypospolitej
      - Socjaldemokracja Rzeczpospolitej Polskiej
      - Unia Demokratyczna
        - General
        - Biuletyn Informacyjny, 1990, 1992-1993
      - Unia Pracy
      - Unia Wolnosci. Statute
      - Zjednoczenie Chrzescijansko Narodowe
        - General
        - Political program
          - General
          - Biuletyn, 1992-1993
        - Ruch Chrzescijansko Narodowy, Akcja Polska (Text 34)
    - Sejm. Publications, 1991-1994
    - Senate. Publications, 1992
    - Social conditions
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1931-1941
  - The English Atlas. Volume I, Containing Description of Poland. Facsimile of 1680 publication (Text 35)
  - Marszalek Pilsudzki w 13 karykaturach Zdzislawa zermanskiego, Paris, Portfolio, 1931.
  - Poland Today: Some of the Principal Matters in the Everyday Life of Poland, Government bulletin on vital statistics, 1939.
  - The port of Gdynia. Map published by Urzad Morski, 1930s
  - Zolnierz w Polu, vol. 1:2, Publication of Polish Airforce staff in England. Mimeographed serial, 1941.
- AUDIO-VISUAL MATERIAL, 1980-1992
  Scope and Contents note
  Microfilm reel, videotape cassettes, phonotape cassettes, and phonotapes
  - 1 microfilm reel on Polish political parties
  - 3 video tapes cassettes (nos. 1-3) of radio broadcast negotiations between leaders of 1980 General strike and government officials
  - Radio broadcast negotiations between leaders of 1980 General strike and government officials, 26-31 August 1980; 7.0 sound cassettes (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet, Cassette 4-10)
    Access
    Radio broadcast negotiations between leaders of 1980 General strike and government officials, Gdansk Shipyard, 31 August 1980, use copy reference number: xx747_a_0009686, xx747_a_0009691
    Radio broadcast negotiations between leaders of 1980 General strike and government officials, Gdansk Shipyard, 26 August 1980, use copy reference number: xx747_a_0009687, xx747_a_0009688
    Radio broadcast negotiations between leaders of 1980 General strike and government officials, Gdansk Shipyard, 31 August 1980, use copy reference number: xx747_a_0009692
    Radio broadcast negotiations between leaders of 1980 General strike and government officials, Gdansk Shipyard, undated, use copy reference number: xx747_a_0009695
  - Radio programs by Solidarity labor union relating to the state of Solidarity and conditions in Poland in general. Includes a conversation with Lech Walesa, 1980-1981; 4.0 sound cassettes (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet, Cassette 11-14)
    Radio program by Solidarity labor union, number 04, use copy number: xx747_a_0009696 Radio program by Solidarity labor union, number 05, use copy number: xx747_a_0009706 Radio program by Solidarity labor union, number 09, use copy number: xx747_a_0009707 Radio program by Solidarity labor union, unnumbered, use copy number: xx747_a_0009710
  - Telephone conversations between Aleksander Pruszynski in Toronto and Maciej Madejski of the Warsaw branch of Solidarity, relating to the state of Solidarity and conditions in Poland in general. Includes a conversation with Lech Walesa, 8.0 sound cassettes (Cassette-cabinet Cassette Cabinet, Cassette 15-22)
    Use copy reference number: xx747_a_0009711
  - Sermon of Jerzy Popieluszko, martyred priest and Solidarity supporter, 1.0 sound cassette (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet, Cassette 23)
    Use copy reference number: xx747_a_0009727
  - Political cabaret, 1988; 1.0 sound cassette (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet, Cassette 24)
    Use copy reference number: xx747_a_0009728
  - Proceedings of three economic and political debates held in Presidential residence, Belweder, 1991; 15.0 sound cassettes (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet, Cassette 25-39)
    Obrady Gospodarcze
    (Names may be misspelled.)
    Part 1, 17 May 1991: 1032 Prezydent RP 1037 Pnerwa 1039 ...... 1039 Boilcerowicz 1059 Kurowski 1118
    Part 2, 17 May 1991: 1118 Kurowski 1124 Ginedu 1153 Pnerwa 1210 Grusiedu 1220
    Part 3, 17 May 1991: 1220 Gruszecki 1225 Janowski 1241 Buycj 1302 Kucyzski 1303 Bungaj 1306 Wiuiecki 1307
    Part 4, 17 May 1991: 1307 Winiedu 1310 Beksick 1316 Manicki 1322 Borszcick 1328 Wiluynski 1333 Chrostowski 1358 Kaleta 1342 Jsolraszcyk 1348 Bozyk 1352 Boilcerowicz 1352
    Part 5, 17 May 1991: 1352 Belcerowicz 1400 Pnerma 1515 Eysymont 1531 Misiek 1539 Goc-Kozierkiewicz 1547 Wcycyk 1554
    Part 6, 17 May 1991: 1554 Woyczyk 1557 Rasilowski 1606 Kaleta 1612 Soblech 1618 Ryblewski 1627 Ryz 1634 Gomotka 1639
    Part 7, 17 May 1991: 1639 Goumutka 1642 Pnerma 1651 Kurowslu 1652 Rybuynslr 1700 Leopold 1704 Doiucq 1710 Dybrowski 1717 Noisitowski 1720 Winiedu 1724 Bretkowski 1728 Nojtowicz 1734
    Part 8, 17 May 1991: 1739 Woytowicz 1740 Welicz 1744 Jolefiak 1748 Wyrzynkiewicz 1755 Podsiadlo 1803 Misiaig 1809 Eysymont 1813 Konieczny 1817 Trzeciakowski 1819
    Part 9, 17 May 1991: 1819 Trzeciakowski
    Part 9, 18 May 1991: 830 Lewandowski 851 Yedraszczyk 908 Krawczyk 915
    Part 10, 18 May 1991: 915 Krawczyk 916 Arguszewski 929 Wyrzynkiewicz 932 Grobnon 941 Przetrzewski 949 Kuczynski 953 Przewodniczacy 955 Kowieczny 1000
    Part 11, 18 May 1991: 1000 Konieczny 1001 Yelczuk 1008 Gruszecki 1013 Przerwa 1026 Bozyk 1033 Fornalczyk 1038 Lewandowski 1046 Yedrasczyk 1049 Stankiewicz 1054 Dabrowsu 1057
    Part 12, 18 May 1991: 1057 Dabrowski 1059 Bugay 1105 Winecki 1112 Kaleta 1117 Leopold 1121 Wilczynski 1126 Misiak 1130 Rybczynski 1133 Palka 1137 Fornalczyk 1139 Borszozak 1142
    Part 13, 18 May 1991: 1142 Borszcick 1149 Winedu 1150 Buguj 1151 Kaleta 1152 Dyskusje 1153 Jgolveszczyk 1154 Pnerwa 1315 Tymowslu 1335 Kamalel 1338 Aulejtner 1347
    Part 14, 18 May 1991: 1347 Auleytner 1353 Slubert 1411 Kantecki 1413 Manicki 1417 Yanowski 1421 Kawalec 1426 Krawczyk 1430 Kurowjki 1432 SL 15A 7B
    Part 15, 18 May 1991: 1432 Kurowski 1435 Pryu...? 1439 ... 1444 Winiecki 1449 Arkuszewski 1453 Boni 1501 Sidorowicz 1505 Bugay 1507 Sidorowicz 1508 Przepna 1525 Przewodniczacz 1526 Winiecki 1534
    Part 16, 18 May 1991: 1534 Wisniecki 1546 Premier 1554 Przewodniczpycu
    Part 17, 18 May 1991: Press conference
    Part 18, 28 August 1991: 1100 ROZPOCIECIE 1103 PLUCINSKI 1115 PRZEWODNICZACV, PLUCINSKI 1120 MACIEREWICZ 1121 GRABUS 1131 NIESIOLOWSKI 1136 MOKEY 1142 SKARADZIMSKI 1150 CYWINSKI
    Part 20: 1234 BOBROWSKI 1238 OLSZEWSKI 1245 GRUDZINSKI 1245 OZSZEWSKI 1253 BOBROWSKI 1254 OLSZEWSKI MACIEREWICZ OLSZEWSKI 1258 MACIEREWICZ NAJDER ------- 1300 DABROWSKI 1301 SKARADZINSKI. OLSZEWSKI, SKARADZINSKI 1304 BOBROWSKI 1305 PLUCINSKI 1306 PLUCINSKI, NAJDER, PRZEWODNICZACY, NIESIOLOUSKI 1313 ZAKONCZENIE
    Use copy reference number: xx747_a_0009733
  - Videotape cassettes on Polish history and politics, In Polish and English, 1986-1989. (Tape-cabinet Tape cabinet)
    - "Pomost: Pierwszy zjazd," Chicago, (nos. 40-41), 1983
    - "Moczulski w Chicago", (no. 42), 1987
    - "O nas i za nas", (no. 43), n.d.
    - "Zbrodnia katynska", (no. 44), n.d.
    - "Bo wolnosc krzyzami sie mierzy: General Anders i jego zolnierze", (no. 45)
    - "Solidarnosc: The Hope from Gdansk", (no. 46), n.d.
    - The Battle for Warsaw videorecording, 1978 (Tape cabinet Oversized VHS, Box 1)
      Documentary by Shanachie about the Battle for Warsaw and guerrilla activities in Poland during World War II. Copyright Peter Batty Productions Ltd. In English. Video transfer from film. Sound. Color and black and white. Duration 48:58.
      Use copy available on-site for immediate use. Use copy reference number: xx747_v_0008558.
  - Phonotape cassettes of martial law period, December 13, 1981- (Text 36-38)
    - American and Canadian broadcasting station reports on developments and issues relevant to the political crisis in Poland
      - December 15(?)-18(?), 1981
      - December 21-23, 1981
      - December 23-27, 1981
      - December 29, 1981 -January 3, 1982
      - January 5-12, 1982
    - "Let Poland Be Poland", United States International Communication Agency production aired on public television in Includes speeches of heads of Western governments, 1982.
    - Przetakiewicz. "Przetakiewicz for Slowo, December 13 or 14, 1981"
  - Phonotape cassettes on Solidarity period, 1980-1981
    - Madejski, Maciej. "Maciej Madejski, 1981, Maria Moczulska, A. Bisping ucieczka z Polski 'How I got out of Urzad Bezpieczenstwa', Bielski, Prawnik(?), Maria Moczulska, May 1981. April 1981"
    - Polskie Radio Wroclaw. Side 1: Interview with Karol Modzelewski and Krzysztof(?) Turkowski on origins of Solidarity movement and social context of 1980 upheaval, recollections of students on August 1981, songs from strike foklore. Recorded on the 1st anniversary of August 1980. Side 2: Ending part of the tape PTV News broadcast on the day of attempt on Pope John Paul II's life, mass at the Wroclaw cathedral on the same evening
    - Radio Free Europe. Side 1: "Migawki z dwoch manifestacji w listopadzie 1/ W Nowym Jorku 21 listopada, 2/ W Warszawie i innych miastach, 11 listopada". Side 2: "Zbrodnie nieujawnione: Poprawka, Szwecja", 1980.
  - Phonotape cassettes of post martial law period, 1983-1988
    - Bratkowski, Stefan. "Gazeta dzwiekowa, no. 7, Uroczystosci pogrzebowe ksiedza Popieluszki", 1984/1985:
    - Bujak, Zbigniew. "Rozmowa z Z. Bujakiem, 2 XII, 1986"
    - Cyran. "Wywiad Cyran I, Gwiazda rozmowa III", n.d.
    - Chojecki, Miroslaw. "Kongres Polonii Amerykanskiej, Illinois Division, Komitet Spraw Polskich. Spotkanie z Miroslawem Chojeckim, 7 maja 'State of Affairs in Poland'. Nagranie Radio 'Victoria', Chicago", 1983:
    - Czestochowa, Mass and sermon at Jasna Gora (Popieluszko ?). Humor of the streets. Accidently interviewed people telling their joke of the day and sharing their daily concerns, 1984.
    - Frasyniuk, Wladyslaw. "Rozmowa z Frasyniukiem, n.d."
    - Glemp, Cardinal. "Cardinal Glemp of Poland, Arrival in Detroit. Press conference(?) in church by Archbishop Szoka. Sermons in two churches in Detroit", 21-22 September 1985.
    - Gwiazda, Andrzej
      - "Andrzej Gwiazda 11 XI, 1986"
      - "Andrzej Gwiazda. Poczatek muzycy z Zawiszy Czarnego. Rozmowa P. Kesik na radiostacji, sierpien Rozmowy o Afryce Poludniowej", 1984.
      - "Rozmowa z Andrzejem Gwiazda 18 V, 1986"
      - "Gwiazda, Frasyniuk, Rulewski, Po podwyzkach w Polsce", April 1987.
      - "Gwiazda, Frasyniuk, Hanzlik 5 III, 1987"
      - "Gwiazda, Frasyniuk, 30 IX, 1987"
      - "Joanna Gwiazda, Jan Rulewski, Bydgoszcz 21 IX. Rozmowy Interview with opposition leaders", 20 September 1985.
      - "Andrzej Gwiazda, 28 February, 1987"
      - "Talk with Andrzej Gwiazda, May 1985"
      - "Andrzej Gwiazda, Zjazd Solidarnosci(?), 22 May, 1987. 1987"
      - "Andrzej i Joanna Gwiazda., 9 February 1986"
      - "Conversation by phone with Andrzej Gwiazda, 7 August 1984"
      - "Andrzej Gwiazda, Interview by phone with Aleksander Pruszynski from Toronto", 9 September 1987.
    - Hanzlik. "Gwiazda, Frasyniuk, Hanzlik 5 III, 1987"
    - John Paul II
      - Voice of America - Pope's trip to Poland in, 1983
        - Pope's sermon at Jagiellonian University; interview with Zbigniew Brzezinski
        - Katowice, Wroclaw, June 19, 1983; June 20, 1983
      - "J. Rozalski from Radio Polish Variete in Detroit speaks on the Papal tour of USA in In Polish, 1987."
      - "Jan Pawel II, Detroit Przemowienie do Polonii po polsku i angielsku, Detroit - Hamtramck", September 1987. 18 September 1987
    - Kocon, Waldemar. "Wlademar Kocon, Detroit, wrzesien 1985. Emigre singer after trip to Australia", September 1985.
    - Kopacsi, Alexander, Colonel. "Hungary, Colonel Kopacsi, Novemeber, 1985"
    - Krol, Maciej. "Marcin Krol, Editor of independent newspaper Republica, July 1987"
    - Kropiwnicki, Jerzy Janusz. "Kropiwnicki, 2 XI(?)"
    - Lenyk, Zygmunt
      - "A. Lenyk, KPN Krakow, A. Gwiazda, maj, 1986"
      - "Rozmowa Zygmunt Lenyk, Krakow, KPN, Interview with Mrs Poray about Polish-Jewish relations, on Poles who helped the Jews survive during the years 1939-1945", maj 1985.
      - "Lenyk Zygmunt, 1 II, 1986"
      - "Lenyk - Rulewski, 22 October 1986"
    - Lis, Bohdan. "Bohdan Lis 9 XII, Andrzej Gwiazda 12 XII (?)"
    - Malkowski, Ksiadz. "1: X Malkowski from Warsaw, the most radical priest in Poland. Easter sermon and interview published in Hutnik in Warsaw, by phone 2: Conversations before Easter 1986 with Andrzej Gwiazda, Gdansk; Maria Moczulska, Warszawa; Jan Rulewski, Bydgoszcz; Zygmunt Lenyk, KPN, Krakow", 21 March 1986.
    - Moczulski, Leszek
      - "Moczulski's first interview after liberation, same day he had a press conference, 22 September 1986"
      - "Moczulski, grudzien Telephone conversation after death of Father Popieluszko", 1984:
      - "Moczulski i Gwiazda, 11 luty, 1987"
      - "Moczulski-Gwiazda, 13 IV, 1987"
      - "Moczulski, I i II, 8-10 IX ", 1984
      - "Moczulski(?) about Podkowa, at Lesna Podkowa, February 85"
      - "Leszek Moczulski z Londynu 9 i 17 stycznia, 1987"
    - Moczulska, Maria
      - "Moczulska, Gwiazda, Lenyk, Rulewski, n.d."
      - "Moczulska. B. dzialacz S Bydgoszcz podejrzany o prace dla SB". Side A: Conversation with Mrs. Maria Moczulska, wife of leader of Konfederacja Polski Niepodleglej, conversation with Mr. Jerzy Pozorski, former member of Solidarity leadership, who allegedly started working for the Polish police, March 1986; 5 April 1986"
      - "Moczulska, Maria, spring 1986"
      - "Moczulska, Maria, Pilgrimage to Czestochowa", September 1986.
    - Mroczek Family. "Lot do wolnosci: Wspomnienia rodziny Mroczek, co uciekla samolotem AN 2 z Polski do Szwecji"
    - Palka, G. "G. Palka, Interview by phone with one of the top leaders from Lodz, member of Prezydium Komisji Krajowej Solidarnosci", 16 October 1987:
    - Polish Parliament in Exile, Chicago. "Session of the Polish Parliament in Exile, May 1986"
    - Romaszewski, Zbigniew
      - "Romaszewski, Warszawa. Nowak and Gil Krakow, February 1985"
      - "Romaszewski, Warszawa, (also "Kopia rozmowy z Rulewskim"), February 1985"
      - "Romaszewski and Hanzlik on Pope's trip to Poland, 10 VI Papiez w Polsce., 1987.
      - "Rozmowa z Romaszewskim z Warszawy i Hanzlikiem z Krakowa, 10 maj, 1987"
    - Rulewski, Jan
      - "Rulewski 25 I Slawikowski, Torun, 28 I 1986"
      - "Rulewski, 14 X Interview for Polish Express (Toronto), 1987.
      - "Jan Rulewski, Bydgoszcz, Joanna Gwiazda, Gdansk. Rozmowy 20 wrzesnia 1985. Interviews with leaders of opposition", 21 9 1985.
    - Sabat, Prezydent. "Prezydent Sabat, 10 XI, 1986"
    - Slowik, Andrzej. "Andrzej Slowik, leader of Solidarnosc' in Lodz, now member of Grupa Robocza, Krajowa Komisja Solidarnosci: Gwiazda - Slowik, 30 X, 1987"
    - Tambo, Oliver. "Tambo, Oliver, leader of the African National Congress. Press conference, Ottawa, September 1987"
    - Walesa, Lech. "Walesa, Paryz, 12 XI Press conference in Paris, 1988".
    - Worthington, Peter. "Canadian journalist Peter Worthington after visit to Angola. Interview for Polish Express, Toronto, October 1985"
  - Phonotape cassettes, 1989-
    - "Spiewnik dla Bezrobotnych", n.d.
- MEMORABILIA, 1980-1993
  Buttons, stickers, lapel pins, propaganda material, T-shirts, election balloons, uniform of Interior Minister
  - Lapel pins from General strike, buttons, elections; T-shirts, 1980; 1993 (Box 39)
  - Uniform of General Czeslaw Kiszczak, Poland's last Communist Minister of Interior and earlier, head of military intelligence (Box 40)
- Incremental Materials
  - Presidential Elections - Aleksander Kwasniewski, 1995 (Box-folder 41: 1)
  - Presidential Elections - Lech Walesa, 1995 (Box-folder 41: 2)
  - Presidential Elections - Jacek Kuron, 1995 (Box-folder 41: 3)
  - Presidential Elections - Waldemar Pawlak, 1995 (Box-folder 41: 4)
  - Presidential Elections - Hanna Gronkiewicz-Waltz, 1995 (Box-folder 41: 5)
  - Presidential Elections - Other Candidates, 1995 (Box-folder 41: 6)
    Tadeusz Kozluk, Adam Strzembosz, Janusz Korwin-Mikke, Kazimierz Piotrowicz, Tadeusz Zielinski, Marek Markiewicz, Jan Olszewski, Jan Pietrzak, Lech Kaczynski, Leszek Moczulski, Stanislaw Tyminski
  - Newspapers - originals and photocopies, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 41: 7)
  - Party Materials - Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 41: 8)
  - Party Materials - Zjednoczenie Chrzescijansko-Narodowe, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 41: 9)
  - Other Election Materials, 1995 (Box-folder 41: 10)
    Cartoon of G. Bush and L. Brezhnev, pisma protestu, "Kto naprawde rzadzi Polska"
  - Election Materials, 1995 (Box-folder 42: 1)
    Jacek Kuron "Raport o stanie Panstwa"
  - Election Materials, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 42: 2)
  - Party Materials, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 42: 3)
    ZChN, Unia Polityki Realnej
  - Polish-German Relations - Print Publications, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 42: 4--5)
    In Polish and German
  - Polish-German Relations - Print Publications, 1995 (Box-folder 42: 6)
    Pamphlets, Newspapers
  - Political Print Materials, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 42: 7)
    Joke books, cartoon of Jaruzelski, poster
  - Solidarity Poems, Songs and Prayers, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 43: 1)
    Some poems by Czeslaw Milosz
  - Solidarity Pocket Calendars, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 43: 2)
  - Solidarity Flyers - Small Size, 1980-1985 (Box-folder 43: 3)
  - Solidarity Flyers - Small Size, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 43: 4)
  - Solidarity Flyers - Medium Size, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 43: 5)
  - Solidarity Flyers - Pocket Size, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 43: 6)
  - Solidarity Posters, Flyers and Bookmarks, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 43: 7)
  - Solidarity Postcards, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 43: 8)
  - Solidarity Postcards, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 43: 9)
  - Solidarity Photographs, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 43: 10)
  - John Paul II - trip to Poland, 1983 (Box-folder 43: 11)
  - Komitet Oporu Spolecznego (KOS) Transparencies, 1983 (Box-folder 43: 12)
  - Jerzy Popieluszko, 1984 (Box-folder 43: 13)
    Proces sprawcow
  - Solidarity Pamphlets, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 44: 1)
  - Solidarity Pamphlets, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 44: 2)
  - Solidarity Pamphlets, 1985 (Box-folder 44: 3)
  - Solidarity Pamphlets, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 44: 4)
  - Solidarity Pamphlets, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 44: 5)
  - Solidarity Pamphlets, Undated (Box-folder 44: 6)
  - Solidarity Documents, 1980-1987 (Box-folder 44: 7--14)
  - Solidarity Documents, Undated (Box-folder 44: 14)
  - Parliamentary Elections - Kongres Liberalno-Demokratyczny, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 45: 1--2)
  - Parliamentary Elections - N.S.Z.Z. Solidarnosc, 1993 (Box-folder 45: 3)
  - Parliamentary Elections - Sojusz Lewicy Demokratycznej, 1993 (Box-folder 45: 4)
  - Parliamentary Elections - Porozumienie Centrum, 1993 (Box-folder 45: 5)
  - Parliamentary Elections - Bezpartyjny Blok Wspierania Reform, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 45: 6)
  - Parliamentary Elections - Polskie Stronnictwo Ludowe, 1993 (Box-folder 45: 7)
  - Parliamentary Elections - Other Materials, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 45: 8)
  - Parliamentary Elections - KPN, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 46: 1)
  - Parliamentary Elections - KPN, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 46: 2)
  - Parliamentary Elections - Unia Demokratyczna, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 46: 3)
  - Parliamentary Elections - Unia Demokratyczna, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 46: 4)
  - Parilamentary Elections - Other Parties, 1993 (Box-folder 46: 5)
    Katolicki Komitet Wyborczy "Ojczyzna", Unia Pracy, Samoobrona
  - Parliamentary Elections - Other Parties, 1993 (Box-folder 46: 6)
    Koalicja dla Rzeczpospolitej, Unia Polityki Realnej, Zjednoczenie Chrzescijansko-Narodowe, Zwiazek Nauczycielski Polskich, Polska Partia Przyjaciol Piwa, Partia "X", Stronnictwo Ludowo-Chrzescijanskie
  - Cassettes (Box-folder 47:)
  - Stefan Bratkowski, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 47: 1)
    9 cassettes
  - Niezalezna Oficyna Wydawnicza, 1983-1987 (Box-folder 47: 2)
    7 cassettes
  - Kora Kraj. X. 1981 (Box-folder 47: 3)
    8 cassettes
  - Neo-Nazi Groups, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 47: 4)
    3 cassettes
  - Testament ksiedza Jerzego, Ks. J. Polpieluszko, undated (Box-folder 47: 5)
    2 cassettes
  - Czerwiec 56, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 47: 6)
  - Jan Pawel II, undated (Box-folder 47: 7)
  - W Marszu do Niepodleglosci, 1920-1995 (Box-folder 47: 8)
  - Pomaranczowa Alternatywa - Waldemar Fydrych, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 48: 1)
  - Pomaranczowa Alternatywa - Pamphlets and Photographs of the happening, 1982-1988 (Box-folder 48: 2)
  - Pomaranczowa Alternatywa - Posters and Graphics, 1982-1988 (Box-folder 48: 3)
  - Pomaranczowa Alternatywa - Press and Other Materials, 1981-1988 (Box-folder 48: 4)
  - Solidarity in Germany - German Bulletin, 1983 (Box-folder 48: 5)
  - Solidarity - Foreign Publications, 1985 (Box-folder 48: 6)
  - List of Holdings of Underground Publications at the Polish Library in Paris, 1982-1989 (Box-folder 48: 7)
  - Indictment of the leadership of Solidarity, 1981 (Box-folder 48: 8)
  - Letter by Jan Rulewski, 1987 (Box-folder 48: 9)
  - Jerzy Popieluszko, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 48: 10)
  - Ration Coupons, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 48: 11)
  - Solidarity Calendars, 1981-1990 (Box-folder 49: 1)
  - Solidarity Pin Buttons and Stickers, 1981-1990 (Box-folder 49: 2)
  - Solidarity Posters, 1981-1990 (Box-folder 49: 3)
  - Solidarity Pamphlets, 1981-1990 (Box-folder 49: 4)
  - Solidarity Announcements, 1981-1990 (Box-folder 49: 5)
  - Opposition Election Posters, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 49: 6)
  - Opposition Documents, 1978-1990 (Box-folder 49: 7)
    Solidarity, KPN, Przelom Narodowy, Ruch Wolnosc I Pokoj
  - Opposition Documents, 1978-1990 (Box-folder 49: 8)
  - Master Mimeograph Plates used for Underground Publishing, 1988 (Box-folder 50: 1)
  - Solidarity Poems and Songs, 1981-1989 (Box-folder 50: 2)
  - Solidarity Posters, Pamphlets and Calendars, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 50: 3)
  - Opposition by the Church, 1980-1989 (Box-folder 50: 4)
  - Underground Publications, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 50: 5)
  - Underground Publications, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 50: 6)
  - Underground Publications, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 50: 7)
  - Ruch Obrony Praw Czlowieka I Obywatela, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 51: 1)
  - Opposition Posters, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 51: 2)
  - Opposition Posters, 1988-1995 (Box-folder 51: 3)
    Solidarity election posters
  - Opposition Materials, 1978-1991 (Box-folder 51: 4)
  - Opposition Materials, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 51: 5)
    Labelled "Unique"
  - Solidarity Pamphlets, 1980-1991 (Box-folder 51: 6)
  - Mysl Demokratyczna, 1989 (Box-folder 52: 1)
  - Election Materials, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 52: 2)
  - Opposition - Foreign Publications, 1988-1995 (Box-folder 52: 3)
  - Comparative Law - Foreign Publications, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 52: 4)
  - Comparative Law - Foreign Publications, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 52: 5)
  - Commissioner for Civil Rights Protection in the Republic of Poland - Reports, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 52: 6)
  - Publications on Transformation and Consolidation, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 52: 7)
  - Polish flag signed by Lech Walesa (Box-folder 53: 1)
  - Boxes 54-64
    Boxes 54-64 are part of the Władysław Chojnacki collection and are listed at the end of the finding aid.
  - VHS Tapes (Box-folder 65: VHS Tapes)
  - Wroclaw at the turn of the 19th Century and today (Box-folder 65: 1)
  - Wroclaw - Przelom XIX I XX wieku oraz dzisiaj (English) (Box-folder 65: 2)
  - Lech Walesa at Stanford May 31, 1996 (Box-folder 65: 3)
  - Lech Walesa at Stanford University May 31, 1996 (Box-folder 65: 4)
  - American Experts about Poland (Box-folder 65: 5)
  - "Pani Henryka to I tamto" Henryka Krzywonos-Strycharska - Eureka Films 1996 (Box-folder 65: 6)